(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
始まりはきっと
It all surely began with
一つの願い
a single wish.
それを抱いて私は
Holding onto that,
生まれた
I was born.
孤独な夜空
In the lonely night sky,
震える指で
with trembling fingers,
点と点を繋げよう
let's connect the dots.
1次元では寂しすぎるから
Because one dimension is just too lonely,
私たちは広がりを求めた
we sought out breadth.
点は線となり
Dots became lines,
線は立体となり
lines became solids,
そこに距離が生まれた
and distance was born.
けれど
But,
3次元ではちょっと遠すぎるから
because three dimensions are a bit too far,
私たちは平面に求めた
we looked to the surface.
点は線となり
Dots became lines,
線は星座となり
lines became constellations,
この夜空を繋ぐよ
connecting this night sky.
自分らしくいられる場所を
A place where I can be myself,
気づけばずっと探していた
I realized I'd been searching for it all along.
煌めく星よ その理に集え
O sparkling stars, gather in that order,
この旗を目印に
with this flag as your guide.
あの日君がいつもそこにいたから
Because you were always there that day,
嬉しくて 続けられたんだ
I was so happy, I could keep going.
今日まで
Until today.
忘れないでね 僕らの星座は
Don't forget, our constellation
君がいたから生まれた
was born because you were here.
たとえ君がいつの時を生きても
No matter what era you live in,
何かを好きになる気持ち
the feeling of coming to love something...
大切に歌い続けてね 僕らの星座は
Please keep singing it with care. Our constellation
君がいるから生まれた
was born because you are here.
夜空に輝き 明日へと繋がる
Shining in the night sky, connecting to tomorrow.
未来を目指すよ
I'll aim for the future.
共に行こう
Let's go together.
これは僕らのキセキ、
This is our miracle,
僕とキミと、大切なあの子の
mine, yours, and that precious girl's,
この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る
chronicling the irreplaceable days spent in this kingdom.
僕たちの物語。
Our story.
小説「FBKINGDOM STORY」ED主題歌抜粋
Novel 'FBKINGDOM STORY' ED Theme Song Excerpt
僕の居る意味はどこにあるの？
Where is the meaning for me being here?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
I can't quite throw away my dreams and hopes,
なんとなく今を生きている
but somehow, I'm living in the now.
あぁ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
There was the scent of fragrant olives.
明日のことも忘れたくなった
It made me want to forget about tomorrow.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
Maybe I should just run away instead.
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I'm the protagonist of a tragedy.
やさしいヒトで居たいな
I want to be a kind person.
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
But even that thought is hypocrisy.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy.
都合良いね、涙が出るの
How convenient, tears are falling.
どれだけ歌っても
No matter how much I sing
この声は君には届かない
This voice won't reach you
どれだけ歌っても
No matter how much I sing
この声は君には届かない
This voice won't reach you
息が苦しくなる
It's getting hard to breathe
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
This song too, will one day come to an end
息が苦しくなる
It's getting hard to breathe
この星もいつかは終わりが来る
This world too, will one day come to an end
金木犀の匂いをまた
The scent of gold osmanthus again...
思い出した
I remembered
In the dust, amidst the wintry wind,
the shadow of the girl...
suddenly, the prologue begins.
気付けば…　駆けだしていた…
Before I knew it... I was running...
揺れ動く…　心のままに…
Following... my wavering heart...
遠ざかる…　白い壁…
Receding... the white wall...
一度も…　振り返らずに…
Without... ever looking back...
《生命》が…　消え逝く季節の…
In the season... where "Life" fades away...
胸を刺す…　気配の中で…
In the air... that stings my chest...
迫りくる…　暗い闇…
Approaching... the dark gloom...
二度と…　明けなないような気がして…
Feeling as if... it will never dawn again...
転がり落ちそうな心
A heart that feels like it might tumble down
必死に抱きとめていた…
I was desperately holding on...
星空へと続く長い坂道は
The long slope leading to the starry sky
永遠にも…　思えたから…
Because it felt... like eternity...
咲く花や…　散りぬるを…
Flowers blooming... and withering away...
神代の《時代》より繰り返す…
Repeating since the age of the gods...
私はそれを…　美しいとは…
I have never... thought that...
思ったことがない…
to be beautiful...
久方の…　春の陽を…
The long-awaited... spring sun...
仮初めの影が奪い合う…
Fleeting shadows fighting over it...
その営みを…　美しいとは…
I have never... thought that...
思ったことがない…
to be beautiful...
諦めながら…　生きてた…
I lived... while giving up...
何も望まないように…　それでも…
Trying not to wish for anything... And yet...
手放せなかった…　最後の願いを…
I couldn't let go... of my last wish...
握りしめて…　駆け上がる
Clutching it tight... I run up
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living recklessly, are laughed at
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で？
In a world where those who live easily gain merit?
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not!
ああ人は滅んでゆく
Ah, people are perishing
綻んでゆく
They are coming apart
才を妬み合い　富を奪い合い
Envying talent, snatching wealth
ああ人は滅んでゆく
Ah, people are perishing
綻んでゆく
They are coming apart
その果てに見えた海は
The sea seen at the end of that
地獄だろうか？ それとも地獄だろうか？
Is it hell? Or is it hell?
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living recklessly, are laughed at
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で？
In a world where those who live easily gain merit?
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶なされて
You who live honestly are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies prosper,
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if time forgets to tick, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will not forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if I work myself to the bone,
感謝されないことも…
There are times I'm not thanked...
「自己犠牲」を受け容れても
Even if I accept "self-sacrifice",
限界がもうやってくるから
The limit is already approaching,
自分を大事に愛せばいい
So it's fine to treasure and love yourself.
それは他人を愛すること
That is loving others.
ああ人は滅んでゆく
Ah, people are perishing.
綻んでゆく
Coming apart.
元に今戻ってゆく
Now returning to how it was.
ああ人は泳いでゆく
Ah, people are swimming.
救われてゆく
Being saved.
君に逢えたから…
Because I met you...
君を愛したから
Because I loved you.
君が闘うなら…
If you fight...
僕も闘うから…
I will fight too...
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You who live recklessly are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easily benefit,
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶なされて
You who live honestly are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies prosper,
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if time forgets to tick, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will not forget!
それじゃあ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight, I'll tell you a story of this kingdom.
嘘か真か、ここに記されている本は内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね。
Whether true or false, the book written here is a mysterious one whose contents change rapidly.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now, I wonder what kind of story it's turned into this time.
これはあるサーカスの一団が王国へ訪れ、
This is a story of a circus troupe that visited the kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが、煌びやかなステージに包まれたお話。
And a still-inexperienced ringmaster who was enveloped in a brilliant stage.
あぁ… これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング！
Ah... this is the dream ending I wanted!
さあ、今日も始まりました～！
Now, it's started again today~!
煌びやか、尊楽のパレード
Brilliant, a parade of noble music
常識もここじゃ無関係 踊れ歌え騒げ全て忘れて
Common sense is irrelevant here. Dance, sing, make a fuss, forget everything
細かいことは置いといて
Put the details aside for now
とりあえず身を任せてみな
Just try leaving yourself to it
幸福を少し分けるような饗宴
A banquet that shares a little happiness
Show Time!
積もりゆく不安や後悔
Accumulating anxieties and regrets
今だけはちょっと目を背けて
Just for now, turn your eyes away a bit
そのままじゃ楽しめないじゃん この場だけは何もかも忘れて！
You can't enjoy it like that! Forget everything just in this place!
幾千の価値観全部 引っ括め楽しませたげる！
I'll make you enjoy all those thousands of values altogether!
百鬼夜行もビックリの隊を成している
Forming a troupe that would even surprise the Pandemonium
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け
A comedy imitating the bizarre opens its curtains
一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
A single glance and you're instantly a captive!?
どんな愛も受け入れてくれる ここだけはあなたの理想郷
Accepting any kind of love, only here is your utopia
「もう間もなく主役の登場、一時でも目を離さないで！」
"The main character is appearing shortly, don't take your eyes off for even a moment!"
眩いほどのステージが始まる
A blindingly bright stage begins
華々しいスポットライトの中 目を奪うような妙技の数々
In the brilliant spotlight, many dazzling feats of skill
この空間が世界で一番 “娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is the most suitable for the name "entertainment" in the world!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手でショーは終わっていく
The show ends with thunderous cheers and applause
「まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが^^;」
"Well, this is just an ideal story though ^^;"
さて、今日も始めましょうか...
Well then, shall we begin today as well...
あ〜、またやっちゃった〜！
Ah~, I did it again!
実際はご覧の通り　まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです
In reality, as you can see,
I'm still just a clumsy apprentice.
先人に憧れ持って　私も！と飛び込んだものの
Looking up to my predecessors,
I dived in thinking, "Me too!"
現実はそんな簡単に　上手くいかないなあ…
But reality isn't that easy,
it's just not going well...
もう一回！　怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け　一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
One more time!
The curtain rises on a comedy mimicking the strange.
One look and you're instantly captivated!?
え？既にそれさっき見た？なら、飽き性なあなたにも朗報
Eh? You've already seen that?
Then here's good news for you, who gets bored easily.
Q.ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ
Q. Just mimicking what came before?
A.繰り返しじゃつまらない！
A. Repetition is boring!
だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
So, let's try changing the presentation from here on!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は　誰にも自分すらも分からない！？
The outcome of this slapstick circus...
No one knows, not even me!?
私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ〜〜〜！！！損させないから
Since you chose me, please enjoy yourself to the fullest!!!
I'll make it worth your while!
いつの日か皆と楽しめる　ショーがしたいんだよな〜！
I want to put on a show
that everyone can enjoy one day!
だからこそ、こんなとこで　挫けるわけとかかな〜い！
That's why I can't afford to give up in a place like this!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない　あの感動を私もいつか…
That emotion that can't be put into words...
I hope to one day...
とても偉大なこのステージに　見合っているか分かんないけれど
I don't know if I'm worthy
of this grand stage yet, but...
観客全て、私の色で　染め尽くしてやろう！
I'll dye every member of the audience in my own colors!
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ〜〜〜！！！
To start with, I'm coming for all of you right in front of me!!!
創造しよう
Let's create it!
華々しいスポットライトの中
Amidst the brilliant spotlights,
目を奪うような妙技の数々
numerous eye-catching feats.
この瞬間が世界で一番　“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This moment is the most worthy in the world
of the name "entertainment"!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で
With thunderous cheers and applause,
ショーが終わっていく
the show comes to an end.
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング。
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for.
これは花の国のお姫様がこの王国へいらっしゃった時のお話
This is a story from when a princess from the Kingdom of Flowers
came to visit this kingdom.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので　国民の大半は、アホの子なんて言ってたけど、
Back then, before everyone knew who she was,
most of the citizens called her a bit of an airhead.
とっても心優しくて気さくで頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ
But she was a very kind, friendly,
and reliable princess.
なんてったって、みこはお姫様なんだから！
Because after all, Miko is a princess!
女神！ 聖女！ 叡智！ 聡明！ 慈愛！ 博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Brilliance! Affection! Philanthropy!
ですわ！　あたしなんてったってお姫様
Desu-wa! After all, I'm a princess.
ハッピーエンドプリンセス
HAPPY END PRINCESS
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life.
ですわー！
Desu-waaa!
一生姫プでイージーモード！って思ったら勝手にご存です！？
Easy mode with 'princess play' for life!
Who said you could decide that!?
世間はいっつも風向き次第
The world always goes where the wind blows.
有象無象ばかりでホント　人間不信になっちゃう
Full of nobodies, honestly,
it makes me lose faith in humanity.
気づいたのこの世界に　血も涙もないこと
I realized that this world
has neither blood nor tears.
あれもダメ
Not that,
これもダメ
not this,
それもダメ
not that either,
どれもダメ
none of it works.
現実は世知辛い
Reality is just bitter.
全部改変ですわ…！
It's time for a total modification...!
あたしなんてったってお姫様
After all, I'm a princess.
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life.
悲しいシナリオを
A sad scenario—
全部全部書き換えちゃうの
I'll rewrite every single bit of it.
だってだってお姫様
Because, because I'm a princess.
自分の物語くらいは
My own story, at least,
キッラキラ楽しまなきゃ　ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I have to enjoy it with some sparkle!
Desu-wa! Desu-wa! Desu-wa!
今にみてなさい！運命なんて
Just you watch! Fate and all that...
改変して差し上げますわ！
I'll modify it all for you!
だれ？だれ？だれ？だれ？　裏で糸を引いてるのはだれ？
Who? Who? Who? Who?
Who's the one pulling the strings behind the scenes?
操り人形だなんて　ごめんだわ全く
Being a puppet...
I'm absolutely not interested.
上品な顔してても　黒幕はあの人かも
Even with an elegant face,
they might be the mastermind.
まずはあたしが　強くならなきゃ
First, I have to become strong.
未来は変わらない
Otherwise, the future won't change.
改革だ…　自分改革ですわ…！
It's a reformation...
A self-reformation, desu-wa...!
そうよなんてったってお姫様
That's right, after all, I'm a princess.
あたしこそ最高権力者
I am the supreme ruler.
生涯すべての
For my whole life,
主導権はこちらにあるわ
I'll be the one in control.
だってだってお姫様
Because, because I'm a princess.
自分で決めたことくらいは
Things I've decided for myself, at least...
わがままに行かなきゃ
Must be selfish
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
女神！
Goddess!
聖女！
Saint!
叡智！
Wisdom!
聡明！
Sagacity!
慈愛！
Benevolence!
博愛！
Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Desu wa!
今日も軽くステップする
Taking light steps today too
運命の歯車が踊りだす
The gears of fate begin to dance
顔を上げたその時
In that moment I look up
ほら世界が恋をする
Look, the world falls in love
あたしハッピーエンドプリンセス
I'm a Happy End Princess
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life
すったもんだある日々も
Even through the ups and downs
全部全部 愛してみせるの
I'll show you I can love it all
ハッピーエンドプリンセス
Happy End Princess
自分の物語くらいは
At least in my own story
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ
I have to enjoy it sparklingly
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
全力で生き抜かなきゃ
Must live life to the fullest
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
今に見てなさい
Just you watch
運命なんて
Things like fate
改変して差し上げますわ！
I shall rewrite them for you!
女神！
Goddess!
聖女！
Saint!
叡智！
Wisdom!
聡明！
Sagacity!
慈愛！
Benevolence!
博愛！
Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Desu wa!
王国で一躍有名になった小説の一つじゃないか。
Isn't this one of those novels that became famous overnight in the kingdom?
...ある女学生探偵と推理作家の先生が織りなす楽しい...
...A fun story woven by a female student detective and a mystery writer...
え？
Eh?
いやいや。この事件が実際にあったのかまではわからないよ。
No, no. Whether this incident actually happened or not, I don't know.
でも、このシリーズは凄い人気なんですよね。
But this series is incredibly popular, isn't it?
わかりました！犯人はあなたですね！
I've got it! You're the culprit!
名探偵連続殺人事件
The Serial Killer Detective Case
作詞・作曲：てにをは
Lyrics/Composition: Teniwoha
あ、あ、あ、カンベコストリートライン
A, a, a, Kanbeko Street Line
七つ道具は捨てちゃえ
Throw away the seven tools
アクロイド殺されたんていが
Ackroyd, the murdered detective
また独り姿を消したという
is said to have vanished once again.
あやなすツツジのアリスは
The Alice of woven azaleas
横溝正史江戸川か
Is it Yokomizo Seishi or Edogawa?
神田伯爵探偵さん
Detective Count Kanda
こんなんどう射ると思う
How do you think this should be shot?
南無阿弥陀仏ステップ
Namu Amida Butsu Step
脳髄これ密室なりや
Is the brain a locked room?
グッドバイであった人
The person met by "Goodbye"
グッドバイで別れましょう
Let's part with "Goodbye"
謎解きはこれから
The mystery solving starts now
「犯人はあなたですね！」
"The culprit is you!"
列車トリック 発火トリック なんちゅう事件
Train trick, ignition trick, what a case
推理作家の先生さん
Mr. Mystery Writer
阿鼻叫喚 裏腹腹 裏腹腹
Agonizing cries, paradoxes, paradoxes
今に見てなさい あーもう 頭がこんがらがってきたけれど
Just you wait and see, ah geez, my head is getting all tangled up, but...
どどど払い ドットコム
Dododo cleaning dot com
あちゃちゃちゃパリパリ エブリバディわんこそば
Achachacha crunchy, everybody wankosoba
「謎はおやつに入りません」
"Mysteries aren't included in snacks"
どどど払い ドットコム
Dododo cleaning dot com
あちゃちゃちゃドシャリドシャリ エブリバディ愛馬、無い、無い、無い
Achachacha crashing down, everybody, no favorite horse, no, no
エセ・ペン・バーバラスな君
You, with the fake pen/barbarous pen
晩餐続いてご静聴
Continuing the dinner, thank you for listening
オリエント急行車の窓
The window of the Orient Express
あの怪盗たちが泣くという
where those phantom thieves are said to be crying.
厚木に二人 海野原
Two in Atsugi, the plain of the sea
坂口安吾 無視したろ
You ignored Sakaguchi Ango, didn't you?
ABCだか海老須だか
Is it ABC or Ebisu?
レモンドちゃんとして
Raymond, do it properly
甲が乙を隠す
Party A hides Party B
そんじゃあ三三六さん お疲れさん
Well then, Mr. 336, good job
死者五人やってみな
Try five dead people
死者五人どこ行った
Where did the five dead people go?
謎解きはまだまだだだだ
The mystery solving is still far from over
「そして誰がいなくなった？」
"And then, who was gone?"
およしになって おやめになって
Stop it, cut it out
怪事件 お下げ揺らす探偵さん
Mysterious case, detective swinging her braids
ネクスト・ベイビー ガストン・ベイビー
Next baby, Gaston baby
行かないで 先生の意地悪は毎度
Don't go, the writer's meanness is constant
どどど払い ドットコム
Dododo cleaning dot com
あちゃちゃちゃパリパリ エブリバディわんこそば
Achachacha crunchy, everybody wankosoba
「たまには自分で考えたまえ」
"Try thinking for yourself for once"
どどど払い ドットコム
Dododo cleaning dot com
あちゃちゃちゃドシャリドシャリ...
Achachacha crashing down...
Everybody アリバイ ない ない ない ない ない
Everybody, no alibi, none, none, none, none, none
怪盗連盟の罠にはまり、次々と姿を消していく名探偵たち。
Falling into the trap of the Phantom Thief League, the great detectives vanish one by one.
そして探偵の居ぬ間に、人々の心は密室となった。
And in the absence of detectives, people's hearts became locked rooms.
「でも、それならどうして私だけが無事だったんでしょうか？」
“But if that's the case, why was I the only one who was safe?”
「その答えはひとつしか考えられない」
“There is only one possible answer.”
「と、言うと……？」
“Which is...?”
「あまりに無能すぎるがゆえに、
“Because you are so utterly incompetent,
君は探偵として勘定に入れられていなかったのだ！」
you weren't even counted as a detective!”
「りゃあああ！」
“Riaaaaa!”
およしになって おやめになって 怪事件
Please stop, please quit this mysterious incident
おさげ揺らす 探偵さん（探偵さん）
Detective-san swinging their braids (Detective-san)
ノックス・ベイビー ヴァン・ダイン・ベイビー 行かないで
Knox baby, Van Dine baby, don't go
and more 先生の いじわる いじわる
And more, sensei's meanness, meanness
列車トリック ハットトリック 難事件
Train trick, hat trick, difficult case
推理作家の先生！
Mystery writer sensei!
うらだぱらだ うらだぱらだ 言わないで
Urada-parada, urada-parada, don't say it
ああもう 頭がこんがらがってきたけど
Ah, my head's getting all tangled up, but
こわいこわいや 通りゃんせ 通りゃんせ
It's scary, scary, let me pass, let me pass
小さい二人の子供が約束した。
Two small children made a promise.
ずっと一緒に笑っていようの約束。
A promise to keep laughing together forever.
今もなお、二人の絆は確かなもので
Even now, the bond between them is certain...
友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語。
A wonderful story woven from friendship and love.
あははっ……なんでもないことに、妙にツボっちゃう時あるよね。
Ahaha... sometimes you just get the giggles over nothing at all, right?
あー 恋に落ちた まゆら 開花 止まらないや
Ah, fallen in love, a faint flickering, the blooming won't stop
何度も捲って 心をかし
Turning the pages over and over, my heart is charmed
泣いてばっかだったの それがどうだい今や
I was always just crying, but how about now?
腹捩れるくらい笑う
Laughing so hard my stomach hurts
ずっと一緒に笑う
We'll always laugh together
君が持ってる 白い花に
The white flower you are holding
あたし見合わない 悲しくなる
Doesn't suit me, it makes me sad
無垢な恋とか 正しさとか
Pure love and righteousness
誰も教えてくれなかった
No one ever taught me about them
昨日会ったばっかで 今日もどっか会えたら
We just met yesterday, but if we could meet somewhere today too
なんて思う暮らし つつましくないよね
Thinking that kind of life isn't very modest, is it?
全部許されたの びっくりしちゃってさ
Everything was forgiven, it really surprised me
涙あふれていたよ
Tears were overflowing
もう愛になる鼻歌 透き通った空に
A hum that's already becoming love, into the clear sky
手を繋いでいった 夢のしるし
We walked hand in hand, a sign of our dreams
どんな前世だってさ 忘れたっていいんだ
Whatever my past life was, it's okay to forget it
きみと笑えるなら
As long as I can laugh with you
心が触れるたび 綺麗な音鳴る
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings out
目と目が合って くすぐったいね
Our eyes meet, and it feels ticklish
なんでもないこと 妙にツボるね
Getting the giggles over nothing at all, right?
全部教えてくれて
For telling me everything
ありがとう
Thank you
きみが持ってる 白い花を
The white flower you are holding
あたしの紅色と合わせたら
If I combine it with my crimson color
霜が解けては 雲が行く
The frost melts and the clouds go by
もう寒くないよ
It's not cold anymore
あー 恋に落ちた まゆら 開花 止まらないや
Ah, fallen in love, a faint flickering, the blooming won't stop
何度も捲って 心をかし
Turning the pages over and over, my heart is charmed
泣いてばっかだったの それがどうだい今や
I was always just crying, but how about now?
腹捩れるくらい笑う
Laughing so hard my stomach hurts
ずっと一緒に笑って
Always laughing together
心をかし
My heart is charmed
ずっと一緒に笑う
We'll always laugh together
最後の日を笑う
Laughing on the final day
これは、遠い遠い名も知らぬ世界で、
This is, in a far, far, nameless world...
死の呪いがかけられた少女のお話
The story of a girl who was cursed with death.
林檎売りの泡沫少女
Apple-Selling Ephemeral Girl
遠い遠い時の果て
At the end of a long, long time
そこに住まう人は皆
Everyone who lives there
永遠の命を持つ
Possesses eternal life
世界での話
This is a story of that world
赤い実の成る木の下
Under the tree that bears red fruit
La La Lu La 生まれながらに
La La Lu La, from the moment of birth
死の呪いがかけられた
Cursed with death
少女の話
The story of a girl
色付いた街外れ
In the colorful outskirts of town
蒼く光る湖畔
By the blue-glowing lakeside
赤い実のお菓子屋
Is a candy shop of red fruit
ちょっぴり寒くなった今日は
Today, it's gotten a bit cold
妙に誇らしげ
She seems strangely proud
自信作を売りにゆく
Going to sell her masterpiece
待ってて 今度こそ
Wait for me, this time for sure
美味しいんだから
Because it's delicious
時計塔の見える市場
In the market with the clock tower
驚いた 珍しく賑やかだね
I'm surprised, it's unusually lively
La La Lu La Lucky!!
物憂げな街の隅 ひとり
Alone in a melancholy corner of town
赤い実のパイはどうですか
How about a red fruit pie?
自信作なの そんなの
It's my masterpiece, but something like that
ひとつも売れないさ
Not a single one will sell
少女を見て蔑む人たち
The people look at the girl with disdain
「みんなと何も変わらないのに」
"Even though I'm no different from anyone else"
美味しくできたのに
Even though I made it so delicious
今日も声は届かないので
My voice doesn't reach them today either, so
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's like I've become transparent
そうして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And so, everyone pretended not to know
何故なら少女は呪われているから
Because the girl is cursed
死んだ世界でただひとり生きていた
She lived all alone in a dead world
少女の話
The story of a girl
夜なべでアレンジパイと
Working through the night on an arranged pie
にっこりスマイル引っさげ
With a beaming smile in tow
少女はまた諦めない
The girl won't give up again
時計塔の針も空を指して
The hands of the clock tower point to the sky
お腹も鳴るそんな時
And her stomach growls at such a time
ふと後ろから人が少女を押す
Suddenly, someone pushes the girl from behind
甘い籠は落ちる
The sweet basket falls
お菓子を踏み行く人たち
People step on the sweets as they go
平気な顔をしてさ
With indifferent faces
惨め拾い集める
She gathers the fragments miserably
ふともうひとりの手が
Suddenly, another person's hand...
ドロドロのパイを頬に口に入れて
Puts the messy pie into their mouth
「美味しいね」
"It's delicious"
その声で心は溢れた
With those words, her heart overflowed
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
It's like an outline has been drawn
そうして彼は手を差し出した
And so, he reached out his hand
何故なら少女に呪われているから?
Is it because he's cursed by the girl?
死んだ世界で運命ふたり生きていた
Two destined souls lived in a dead world
遠い物語
A distant story
街の人達は哀れむ
The people of the town feel pity
赤い実を食べて呪われた者を
For the one who ate the red fruit and was cursed
「永遠に生きられずに死ぬのさ」
"They'll die without being able to live forever"
嘯いて なんて可哀想な話
They boast; what a pitiful story
ふたりは笑う それでも笑う
The two of them laugh, they laugh anyway
La La La とっても素敵な呪いで
La La Lu La, with a very wonderful curse
たとえ明日死んでも
Even if they die tomorrow
今が確かで大切になるから
Because the present becomes certain and precious
もう声は届かないので
The voice no longer reaches anyone, so
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's like I've become transparent
そうして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And so, everyone pretended not to know
何故なら世界が呪われているから
Because the world is cursed
『永遠』の呪いは解かれていた
The curse of "eternity" had been broken
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだわ
It's like the two of them were the ones who went mad
そしていつか笑うように眠る
And one day, sleep as if smiling.
なぜなら二人は放たれているから
Because the two of us are set free.
死んだ世界でただ二人だけが幸せだった
In a dead world, only the two of us were happy.
さあ
Now.
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう。
Now, let's call it a day.
...そろそろ時間になりましたし。
...It's about that time.
え？どこへ向かうのかって？
Eh? You're asking where I'm headed?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Don't you know what day it is today?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティーですよ！
Today is the Halloween party in the underworld, deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです。
It's an annual festival where the dead and the living enjoy themselves.
さあ、一緒に向かいましょう。
Now, let's head there together.
でも、気を付けて。
But, be careful.
パーティーとはいえ、死者が住まう冥界です。
Even if it's a party, it's the underworld where the dead reside.
誰かの思念や死者たちによって奇妙なことが起こるかもしれません。
Strange things might happen due to someone's thoughts or the dead themselves.
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾けすぎてはいけませんよ...
But you must never listen too closely to them...
それでは、参りましょう。
Well then, let's go.
蒼炎
Blue Flame
作詞・作曲：景乃
Lyrics/Composition: Kageno
誰かが言いました
Someone once said,
激しく燃えるものほど
The more intensely something burns,
煌めく引き換えに
In exchange for its sparkle,
その身をすぐ焦がしきると
The sooner it burns itself out.
数ある燭台に
Upon the many candle holders,
お好きな火を灯しましょう
Let's light the flame of your choice.
期待と裏腹に
Contrary to expectations,
燻ればお生憎様
If it smolders, my condolences.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran.
右手には錆びた時計
In my right hand, a rusted watch.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran.
左には油の筒
In my left, a tube of oil.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran.
絽のドレスを着飾って さあ
Dressed up in a silk gauze dress, now,
激しく 儚く 蒼く燃ゆる花びら
Violently, fleetingly, blue-burning petals.
瞬き ゆらめく 生を彩り照らせ
Twinkling and flickering, illuminate life with color.
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
Toward a future that will eventually run out.
ゆりかごの目の前で
In front of the cradle,
遍く飛び交う銃弾
Bullets fly everywhere.
指だけ動かせば容易くその火は潰える
With just a movement of a finger, the flame easily dies out.
仮初めの情熱で 焼け爛れた舌では
With a temporary passion, and a scorched and raw tongue,
上手に喋ることができないようで
It seems I cannot speak well.
喉元過ぎても 毒を孕ませて
Even after it's passed the throat, let it harbor poison,
やがては腑を腐らせる
And eventually rot the guts.
やがては腑を腐らせるでしょう
Eventually, it will rot your guts.
揺らぐ死と生の狭間
Between flickering life and death
焼ける心と歌う
Singing with a burning heart
描いた最愛の終幕を
The beloved finale I drew
激しく 儚く
Intense, fleeting
青く燃ゆる花びら
Blue-burning petals
瞬き ゆらめく
Twinkling and flickering
生を彩り照らせ
Color and illuminate life
いずれ尽き果てるその先へと
Towards what lies beyond exhaustion
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
We must hurry to the venue before we're dragged into that other world.
気を付けてついてきてくださいね。
Please be careful and follow me.
あまり深入りすると、おっと…
If you get too deep into it, oops...
そうそう、知らないほうがきっと懸命ですよ。
That's right, it's probably for the best that you don't know.
なんだかすっごく心地が良いよね。
It feels really good somehow, doesn't it?
気づけば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I knew it, I was standing in an unknown world
何処かも分からず毎日毎日泣いていた
Not knowing where I was, I cried every single day
なんて暇もなく
But there's no time for that!
Happy Time おかしな面々が
Happy Time! Strange people
Happy Time おどけて転がるの
Happy Time! Playfully rolling around
Happy Time その馬鹿馬鹿しさに希望も恐怖もなくなった
Happy Time! In that absurdity, hope and fear have vanished
確かそうアタシには為すべき仕事愛の棲家
Indeed, for me, there is work to be done in this nest of love
パンプキン ヘッドギア
Pumpkin, Headgear
だけどなんかどーでもいい
But somehow, none of it matters
さぁ始まった夢の夜だ
Now it's begun, this night of dreams
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
The music resonates and won't stop
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Raise your voices and shout today
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
Jack-o'-lantern, pranks, it's a free-for-all!
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously just doesn't pay off
なんでもありさ なぜって今日は
Anything goes, because today is
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
消えちゃった 消えちゃった
Gone, they're gone
出口はないんだって そう永遠に
There's no exit, they say, for eternity
消えちゃった 消えちゃった
Gone, they're gone
思想 ルール 倫理 関係ない
Thought, rules, ethics, they don't matter
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
「私はロボットではありません」に
To "I am not a robot"
無心でチェックし解答するけれど
I mindlessly check and answer
本当にそうかな
But is it really true?
Happy Life とりま音に乗せて
Happy Life! For now, ride the sound
Happy Life デタラメに踊るの
Happy Life! Dance haphazardly
Happy Life その繰り返しのなか懐疑心も失った
Happy Life! In that repetition, skepticism was lost too
意志のない様まるで
Like a being without a will
ロボトミーした電気羊
A lobotomized electric sheep
ナイトメア NPC
Nightmare NPC
だけどなんか心地がいい
But somehow, it feels good
おっと音声が乱れました
Oops, the audio got distorted
お気になさらずに皆々様
Please don't mind it, everyone
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
Let's sew up those mouths
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
Chocolate and candy for the mouths of good children
歯に絹着せっちゃ噛み合わない
Mincing words just won't cut it
気を取り直し みんなでどうぞ
Let's regain our composure and join in, everyone
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
全部全部理解した
I understood everything, everything
だから何も見たくねぇわ
So I don't want to see anything anymore
さぁ始まった夢の夜だ
Now it's begun, this night of dreams
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
The music resonates and won't stop
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Raise your voices and shout today
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
Jack-o'-lantern, pranks, it's a free-for-all!
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously just doesn't pay off
なんでもありさ なぜって今日は
Anything goes, because today is
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
泣いちゃった 泣いちゃった
Crying, I ended up crying
知らない方がきっと懸命ね
It's probably for the best that you don't know
泣いちゃった 泣いちゃった
Crying, I ended up crying
このパーティーに終わりはない
This party has no end
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT!
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
お菓子をくれてもイタズラはしちゃうよ！
Even if you give us treats, we'll still play tricks on you!
狂笑トリックスターズ / 作詞・作曲：OSTER project
Kyoushou Trickstars / Lyrics, Composition: OSTER project
ようこそ everyone 見の毛もよだつこの spooky night
Welcome everyone to this hair-raising spooky night
腹の底まで揺れ kick & bass & hats & trumpet
Shake to the core with kick & bass & hats & trumpet
ランタンと swingin' beat 赤い目で踊り狂えば
Lanterns and a swinging beat, if you dance like crazy with red eyes
浮世の憂いも忘れられるでしょ
You'll be able to forget the sorrows of the transient world, right?
諸行無常 ちまたじゃ お化けよりも怖い人たち
All things are impermanent; in the streets, people are scarier than ghosts
増えすぎちゃってすぐに 1out, 2out, 3out ノックアウト
They've increased too much, so quickly it's 1out, 2out, 3out, knockout!
コンプライアンスも 厳しい世の中ですが
Even in this world of strict compliance
恐怖のリライト 請け負い申します
We undertake the rewriting of fear
Give me a cherry pie それとも may I choke you up?
Give me a cherry pie, or may I choke you up?
Give me a flowy dress それとも may I stab you to death?
Give me a flowy dress, or may I stab you to death?
Rope, box, cake, knife, scissors, razor blade
Choose one... choose one... choose one...
「さぁ選んで」
“Now, choose.”
なんちゃって ドッキリ大成功！
Just kidding, the prank was a huge success!
響くパンパカパンパンファンファーレで
With the echoing fanfare
にっこり笑っちゃってはい、ポーズ！
Smile and say cheese!
あー怖かったなーなんて 坐り込んで涙目で
Saying “Oh, that was scary,” sitting down with teary eyes
笑う顔見たいな
I want to see your smiling face
ちっちゃな箱の中の モンスターに怯えにゃいなら
If you're not afraid of the monster in the small box
いつだってここに おいで
Come here anytime
もっとずっと本能的で楽しくなれる
You can become much more instinctive and have fun
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with fear
森羅万象 キワまでカタルシス
All things in nature, catharsis to the limit
もういっちょ 感情ジェットコースターで ゴキゲンデトックス
One more time, a happy detox on an emotional roller coaster
満月が暴く 醜悪な本性
The full moon reveals a hideous true nature
デタラメに杖振り回し hocus pocus
Waving a wand randomly, hocus pocus
劣等感を餌に 育つ呪いを
The curse that grows by feeding on inferiority complexes
摘み取る術を知ってるかい？
Do you know the way to pluck it out?
「迷える哀れな子羊たちよ」
“You poor, wandering lambs”
「お菓子が欲しいかい？ それとも安らぎが欲しいかい？」
“Do you want candy? Or do you want peace?”
永遠に求め続けるの？ それならばずっと苦しいままだ
Will you keep seeking forever? Then you'll remain in pain forever.
恐怖からの解放によって 成し得る救済があるのならば
If there is salvation that can be achieved through liberation from fear
この目隠しはそのままで
Keep this blindfold on
「さぁ、イタズラ完了」
“Now, the trick is complete.”
永遠に断ち切れない 呪いの鎖に囚われ
Trapped in a chain of curses that can never be broken
朽ち果ててしまう前に
Before you rot away completely
脳みそちょっといじるだけで あら不思議
Just a little tinkering with the brain, and oh, look!
こんなに気持ち良くて 気分爽快
It feels so good, so refreshing
なんちゃって ドッキリ大成功！
Just kidding, the prank was a huge success!
響くパンパカパンパンファンファーレで
With the echoing fanfare
にっこり笑っちゃってはい、ポーズ
Smile and say cheese!
あー怖かったなーなんて へたり込んで涙目で
Saying “Oh, that was scary,” collapsing with teary eyes
笑う顔見たいな
I want to see your smiling face
もう苦しまなくていいよ こんなに頑張ったんだから
You don't have to suffer anymore, because you've worked so hard
躊躇わずこっちにおいで
Don't hesitate, come over here
もっとずっと本能的に気持ち良いいだけの
Just something that's much more instinctively pleasant
ゴールを見せてあげる
I'll show you the goal
脳漿埋まってまで光るカタルシス
Catharsis that shines until the brain is buried
もういっちょ 因果全リセットで 魂デトックス
One more time, a soul detox with a full reset of karma
いつかの、あったかもしれない世界の出来事までも、
Even the events of a world that might have existed once,
この冥界ではこうして思念として漂っているんだね。
They drift as thoughts here in the underworld.
あまり深入りしてはいけないよ。こういうのが一番たちが悪い。
Don't delve too deeply. These things are the most troublesome.
私はただ、あなたを愛していただけ。
I just... loved you.
物言わぬ唇に生気を吹き込んで
Blowing life into wordless lips
今宵「あなた」は甦る あの頃の姿で
Tonight, “you” shall be revived in your form from those days
ネクロの花嫁 / 作詞・作曲・奏音69
The Bride of Necro / Lyrics, Composition: Kanon69
白肌の娘が指をさした。
A girl with white skin pointed her finger.
「この身体貴方に捧げるわ」
"I offer this body to you."
白服の医者がささやいた。
A doctor in white whispered.
「迎えに行くよ」
"I'm coming to pick you up."
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた。
The girl with white skin decayed.
世界のだれにも見捨てられ、
Abandoned by everyone in the world,
白服の医者は哀れんで、
The doctor in white took pity on her,
誰も知らない場所で眠らせた。
And let her sleep in a place no one knows.
朽ちてもまだ 美しい顔で、
Even in decay, with a beautiful face,
ふたりしかいない霊廟で、
In a mausoleum where only the two of them were,
医者は恋をした。
The doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。
Is it eternal love?
禁断の行為か。
Or a forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
I only wish to meet again.
それが罪なのでしょうか。
Is that a sin?
物言わぬ口唇に
Into the silent lips,
生気を吹き込んで、
he breathed life,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。
Tonight, the two will be united.
祝福もされずに。
Without any blessing.
飾られた眼窩に青いガラスを。
Blue glass in the adorned eye sockets.
破れかけた腕に絹の薔薇を。
Silk roses on the torn arms.
侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを。
Cotton gauze on the affected internal organs.
宝石で飾った白いドレス。
A white dress adorned with jewels.
朽ちゆくたび
Every time she decays,
取り繕って、
he mends her,
恋を唄って、
Singing of love,
また医者は
once again the doctor
手を染め続けた。
continued to stain his hands.
やがて暴かれたのは
Eventually, what was revealed
醜い怪物で、
was an ugly monster,
それを作り上げた医者は
and the doctor who created it
弁駁を叫んだ。
shouted his refutation.
「これは永遠の恋だ。
"This is eternal love.
彼女の願望だ。」
It's her wish."
死にゆくと決めたお前らが
Aren't you the ones who decided she'd die
見捨てた女じゃないか！
and abandoned her?!
嗚呼…哀しき花嫁。
Ah... the sorrowful bride.
物言えぬままで、
Still unable to speak,
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。
Tonight, the two will be judged.
彼女を見捨てた 人達の正義で。
By the justice of those who abandoned her.
正しいのはだあれ？
Who is the right one?
さて、ハロウィンパーティーもついにフィナーレ。
Well, the Halloween party has finally reached its finale.
ここでご参加くださった国民の皆様へ
And now, to all the citizens who participated,
冥界からのお土産品のご紹介です。
I'd like to introduce some souvenirs from the underworld.
お土産品は全4種類。
There are four types of souvenirs in total.
フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には特典もございます。
There's also a special bonus for those who purchase the full set.
ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう。
Let's take a closer look together.
まず1つ目。
First, the first one.
今回の冥界ハロウィンナイトをイメージしたワイドラバーマットです。
A wide rubber mat inspired by this underworld Halloween night.
国王様の横には冥界の女王の姿が。
Beside the King is the Queen of the underworld.
名を、ナイラというそうです。
Her name is said to be Nayla.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんでほしいという気持ちを込めた
With the wish for everyone to fully enjoy the underworld's Halloween,
彼女のイメージソングも、この後お披露目予定なのでお楽しみに。
her image song will also be revealed later, so look forward to it.
素敵なイラストは、抹茶様に描いていただきました。
The wonderful illustration was drawn by Matcha-sama.
2つ目は、パスポート風王国シール帳です。
The second one is a passport-style Kingdom sticker book.
このシール帳にはこれからたくさんの思い出を記していきたいですね。
I want to record many memories in this sticker book from now on.
王国の軌跡として国民の皆様も
As a record of the Kingdom's history, I hope you all,
今後集めてみてはいかがでしょうか。
the citizens, will try collecting them too.
その一歩として今回のキービジュアルのステッカーを1枚封入しております。
As a first step, a sticker of this time's key visual is included.
3つ目は、すこん部FACTORYより、
Third, from Sukon-bu FACTORY,
キングフブちゃんぬいぐるみです。
the King Fubu-chan plushie.
こちらは国王自らデザインをしており、とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております。
This one was designed by the King himself, and it's a very adorable plushie.
前回のVol.1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は、ご一緒に飾ってあげてくださいね。
If you have the plushie from Vol. 1, please display them together.
4つ目は、王国リボンチャームです。
The fourth one is the Kingdom ribbon charm.
こちらは秘書である私の胸元のリボンが再現されております。
This one is a reproduction of the ribbon on the chest of my secretary self.
カバンにつけたり...
You can attach it to your bag...
...にもよし、ペンライトにつけるもよしと
...or attaching to a penlight,
多機能なリボンチャームとなっておりますので、
it's a versatile ribbon charm,
皆様の「推し活」とやらにぜひご活用ください。
so please use it for your 'oshikatsu' activities.
最後は特典のお知らせです。
Lastly, here's information about the bonus.
フルセットをご購入の方全員に、
チェキ風ブロマイドカードを1つお付けいたします。
Everyone who purchases the full set will
receive one cheki-style bromide card.
複製サインと国王からの
メッセージもあるそうですよ。
It apparently includes a printed signature
and a message from the King.
数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン入りですので、
皆様お早めに。
The limited edition version features a hand-signed
signature, so please get yours early.
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした。
That concludes this time's souvenir introduction.
さて、この後は冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲、
Now, after this, a song inspired by
the Queen of the Underworld,
「冥界Halloween Night!」のお披露目です。
the premiere of 'Meikai Halloween Night!'.
楽しまれた後は、
無事、王国へお帰りくださいね。
After enjoying it, please return safely
to the Kingdom.
それでは。
Well then.
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come on, let's dance.
This is Halloween Night!!
冥界をあげての Party (Party)
A party involving the entire underworld (Party)
ルール違反はダメですよ Warning (Warning)
Violating the rules is not allowed, Warning (Warning)
説明は一度きり (きり)
The explanation is only once (once)
聞き逃せばあの世行き
If you miss it, you're off to the next world.
冗談ですよ♡
Just kidding! ♡
(はい！) お菓子を持って
(Yes!) Holding candy
(はい！) 仮装して舞って
(Yes!) Dancing in costume
生者か死者かは隠すこと (よー！)
Whether you're living or dead, keep it hidden (Yo!)
(はい！) いつだって顔で
(Yes!) Always with a ... face
(はい！) 油断禁物で
(Yes!) Being careless is forbidden
最後の最後はご無事で帰ること
In the very end, return home safely.
一人きりじゃつまらないわ
Being all alone is boring,
この退屈な城の玉座で
on the throne of this tedious castle.
指を鳴らして待ちわびてた
I've been snapping my fingers, waiting impatiently.
人恋しいとか？
Am I feeling lonely for people?
やだ！そんなんじゃないってば！
No! I'm telling you, it's not like that!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night!!
Let's underworld Halloween Night!!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night.
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-ta, rat-tat-ta, underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A spine-chilling and pleasant irony.
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム!
Rat-tat-ta, rat-tat-ta, the showtime of the mad banquet!
(パパパ) 恐ろしや
(Pa-pa-pa) How terrifying.
(うらめしや) 恨めしや
(Urameshiya) How resentful.
夢もお名前も忘れてる
Forgetting dreams and even names.
おろろ？
Ororo?
(パパパ) おいしそう
(Pa-pa-pa) Looks delicious.
(はい！) 魂だーわ
(Yes!) It's a soul!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come on, let's dance.
This is Halloween Night!!
響くガラクタなチューニング (チューニング)
Resonating junk tuning (Tuning)
その不協和音さえもミュージック (ミュージック)
Even that dissonance is music (Music)
王座のドアが開き (開き)
The throne door opens (Opens)
拍手喝采が起こる
A round of applause occurs.
快感です♡
It's a pleasure. ♡
(はい！) ろうそくを灯して
(Yes!) Lighting candles
(はい！) ドレス纏って
(Yes!) Wearing a dress
(ぜん！) 女王の私のお出ましです！ (おー！)
(All!) Here comes the Queen, me! (Oh!)
(はい！) 手を取り合って
(Yes!) Taking each other's hands
(はい！) 今日は無礼講で
(Yes!) Today is a free-for-all
私に見惚れちゃったら最後です♡
If you're entranced by me, it's the end. ♡
鮮やかなステップ くるり舞ってワルツ
Vivid steps, turning and dancing a waltz,
百鬼夜行のリズムに揺られて
swaying to the rhythm of the Night Parade.
この楽しさ癖になるわ
This fun is becoming addictive.
時間切れとか…
Running out of time...
やだ！全然足りないってば！
No! I'm telling you, it's not enough at all!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night!!
Let's underworld Halloween Night!!
Dancing! Dancing! 一夜の奇怪なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! A strange memory of one night.
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-ta, rat-tat-ta, underworld Halloween Night!
Sweety! Sweety! おもむろに頬張るキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Slowly stuffing cheeks with candy.
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ あもっと頂戴！
Rat-tat-ta, rat-tat-ta, oh give me more!
泡沫の夢 淡い霧の中溶けて
Fleeting dreams melting in the faint mist,
青白い頬を 涙が伝った
tears trickled down pale cheeks.
この命は誰のため？自問自答の末
For whom is this life? At the end of self-reflection,
禁断の箱 開けたら
once the forbidden box is opened...
時間を戻す
Reverse time,
魔法使っちゃおうかな♡
maybe I'll use some magic. ♡
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night.
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-ta, rat-tat-ta, underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A spine-chilling and pleasant irony.
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム!
Rat-tat-ta, rat-tat-ta, the showtime of the mad banquet!
(パパパ) 恐ろしや
(Pa-pa-pa) How terrifying.
(うらめしや) 恨めしや
(Urameshiya) How resentful.
夢もお名前も忘れてる
Forgetting dreams and even names.
おろろ？
Ororo?
(パパパ) おいしそう
(Pa-pa-pa) Looks delicious.
(はい！) 魂だーわ
(Yes!) It's a soul!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come on, let's dance.
This is Halloween Night!!
ハロウィンパーティー、いかがでしたでしょうか？
How was the Halloween party?
ちゃんとこちら側の王国に戻って来られていますか？
Were you able to return to this kingdom safely?
冥界の女王様に気に入られてしまうと、魂を奪われてしまって帰って来られませんからね。
If the Queen of the Underworld takes a liking to you, she'll steal your soul and you won't be able to come back.
戻って来られてラッキーでした... なんて。
You were lucky to be able to return... just kidding.
あ、今日のお話はどうでしたか？楽しかったでしょうか？
Ah, how were today's stories? Did you enjoy them?
私が特にお気に入りは探偵のお話でして、今回お聞かせできてとても嬉しかったです。
My particular favorite was the detective story, and I'm very happy I could share it with you this time.
そうだ、いつかあなたのお話も聞かせてくださいね。
That's right, please tell me your story someday, too.
もしかすると、あの本にあなたのお話も書き記されるかもしれませんよ。
Perhaps your story will be recorded in that book as well.
なんといっても、摩訶不思議な本ですから。
After all, it's a mysterious book.
何が起こるか、司書である私にもわかりません。
Even I, the librarian, don't know what will happen.
さて、そろそろお時間ですね。
Well, it's about time.
またお話が聞きたくなりましたら、いつでもこの王国図書館へお越しください。
If you ever want to hear a story again, please come to this Kingdom Library anytime.
それでは、さようなら。
Well then, goodbye.
ハジマリはきっとひとつの願い
The beginning was surely a single wish
それを抱いて私は生まれた
I was born holding onto it
孤独な夜空
In the lonely night sky
震える指で 点と点をつなげよう
With trembling fingers, let's connect the dots
LIVE Blu-ray 発売決定！
LIVE Blu-ray Release Decided!
すこん部の皆さん！準備はできてますか？
Everyone in Sukon-bu! Are you ready?
Say! Fanfare! 行きますよー！
Say! Fanfare! Here we go!
Say! ほらどの顔あげて
Say! Look, lift up your face
みんなで手をとれば
If we all hold hands
High! まだまだ道半ば
High! We're still only halfway there
世界を越えよう
Let's go beyond the world
Say! ほら推し推しがまま
Say! Look, just as you like
止まらない全力ですから
Because I'm going at full power without stopping
夢を書き換えたら
If we rewrite our dreams
追いかけ続けよう
Let's keep chasing them
ともにつなぐファンファーレ Go!
The fanfare that connects us, Go!
Yeah!
ハイ！ハイ！うーここ！
Yes! Yes! Woo, here!
なかなか苦い姿 自分自身の
Quite a bitter sight, of myself
輝きを見失った
When I lost sight of my brilliance
時には思い出してね
Please remember
僕らのステージは
Our stage
君がいるから輝く
Shines because you are here
Oh Yeah! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah! Among countless stars
Oh Yeah! 光を君がくれた
Oh Yeah! You gave me light
Oh Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah! もっと
Oh Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah! More
Oh Yeah! 越えて行けるさ
Oh Yeah! We can go beyond
Oh Yeah! スーパーノバ起こせ今
Oh Yeah! Create a supernova now
Oh Yeah! 何度だって飛べる
Oh Yeah! We can fly any number of times
Oh Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah! これは
Oh Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah! This is
まぎれもなく僕らの奇跡
None other than our miracle
Hi Friends!
Blu-ray 発売決定！！詳細は後日！お楽しみに！！
Blu-ray Release Decided!! Details at a later date! Look forward to it!!
Best wishes! すこん部ー！
Best wishes! Sukon-bu!